pocketwizard.com 2018-11-11

# PocketWizard® - Privacy Policy

**PRIVACY POLICY**

Lab Partners Associates, Inc. d/b/a LPA Design ("LPA") has created this Privacy Policy ("Privacy Policy") to demonstrate its commitment to fully disclosing the information collection and use practices applicable to this Internet website (the "Site").  

**By using or accessing the Site, you signify your acceptance of the terms of this Privacy Policy.   If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Site, products and/or services and exit the Site immediately. **

**1.   _Types of Information Collected On The Site And Method of Collection_ **

**A.   General Information Collection **

  * _By Browsing_.  As you browse the Site the Internet protocol (IP) address of your computer will be collected by a third party entity to evaluate Site traffic and usage patterns.  LPA will not have access to data pertaining to individual site visitors.  Such information is aggregated with tracking data from all visitors to the Site.  If you only browse this Site, you are not required to identify yourself or provide any personally identifiable information.  For purposes of this Privacy Policy, the term "Personally Identifiable Information" refers to any information that identifies or can be used to identify, contact, or locate the person to whom such information pertains.

  * _By Site Requirement_.  You will be required to provide Personally Identifiable Information in the following circumstances:

    * To register as a member of the POCKETWIZARD blog ("Blog") you will be required to provide a user name that you create and a personal, active e-mail address to Auttomatic Inc. ("Auttomatic"), the company which hosts the Blog through its website at WordPress.com. 

    * To register your product on the Site you will be required to provide your name, address, e-mail address, date the product was purchased, country from which the product was purchased, product name, and product model and serial number.

    * If you send a message or inquiry to LPA you will be required to provide your e-mail address.

  * _By User's Voluntary Submission_.  You may voluntarily provide Personally Identifiable Information in the following circumstances:

    * When commenting on the Blog hosted by Auttomatic you may choose to provide Personally Identifiable Information, such as your residential or business contact information.  If you post Personally Identifiable Information anywhere on the Blog, it will be subject to Auttomatic's Privacy Policy at WordPress.com.  Such information will be available to third parties and you may receive unsolicited messages from those parties.  LPA has no obligation to ensure the security or confidentiality of any information you choose to make available anywhere on the Blog.  Also, LPA cannot ensure that third parties who have access to such information will respect your privacy.  Please exercise caution when deciding to disclose Personally Identifiable Information. 

    * If you register a product on the Site, you may choose to provide your company name, job position, or telephone number.

    * If you send a message or inquiry to LPA, you may choose to provide your name and telephone number, or other Personally Identifiable Information in your message or inquiry.

**B.   Cookies**

In the customer service and warranty portions of the Site, LPA uses a feature of your browser to set "cookies" on your computer.  Cookies may also be set by Auttomatic when you use the Blog.  To learn about how Auttomattic uses cookies, please review its Privacy Policy on WordPress.com.  Cookies are small packets of information sent by the Site through your browser to your computer.  LPA uses cookies to save information that you submit to the Site so you do not have to re-enter it each time you visit theSite.  These cookies can be deleted or modified through your browser Internet settings.  If you do not want your browser to accept cookies, you can turn off the cookie acceptance option in your browser's setting.  You may modify your browser preference to provide you with choices relating to cookies.  You have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set or to reject all cookies.  If you choose to reject cookies you may be unable to use those LPA services that require registration in order to participate, will have to sign in each time you visit the Site, or may not be able to utilize fully all of the Site's features and information.

 **C.   Information on Children **

LPA does not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13.  Product registration and Site usage is not intended for people under the age of 13.  If LPA learns that it has Personally Identifiable Information on a child under the age of 13, LPA will delete that information from its systems.  LPA encourages parents and guardians to monitor children's online usage.  Parental control protections, such as computer hardware, software or filtering services, are commercially available to limit the access to material that is harmful to minors.

 **2.   _How Information Collected On The Site Is Used By LPA_**

The information collected by and through the Site is owned solely by LPA and will be used, in whole or in part, by LPA and its subsidiaries, affiliates, distributors, and other entities that may be involved in the operation of this Site.  The third parties that LPA shares Personally Identifiable Information with and the use of that information by such third parties is discussed more fully in Sections 3 and 4.

LPA may use the information collected by and through this Site, individually or in an aggregate form, as follows: 

  * to contact you about the Site.  For example, LPA may use the information to inform you of changes to this Privacy Policy and the Terms of Use Agreement of the Site, to inform you that you have violated the Terms of Use Agreement, to inform you that the Site is suspended for maintenance, or to inform you of a change in ownership or control of the information collected by and through the Site; 
  * to evaluate products and services LPA could offer to you; 
  * to monitor or improve use of the Site;
  * to monitor compliance with LPA's Terms of Use Agreement of the Site; 
  * to track products that you have purchased;
  * to track your product warranties, service requests, repairs, and technical support inquiries; 
  * to send you product update bulletins for products that you have purchased; and
  * to respond to inquires you send to LPA.

The Site, LPA, and/or a subsidiary or division of LPA may be sold along with its assets, or other transactions may occur in which your Personally Identifiable Information is one of the business assets transferred.  In such a case, your Personally Identifiable Information, which LPA has collected, may be one of the business assets LPA transfers. 

LPA reserves the right to disclose the information collected by and through this Site, including your Personally Identifiable Information, as required by law and when LPA believes that such disclosure is necessary (i) to protect LPA's rights, a third party's rights, or the rights of the public at large; or (ii) to comply with a judicial proceeding, subpoena, court order or other legal process served on LPA.  The disclosure of this information may be without notice to you.

 **3.   _With Whom LPA Shares Information Collected On This Site_**

LPA may share the Personally Identifiable Information collected by and through this Site with its subsidiaries, affiliates, distributors, and entities that may be involved in the operation of this Site.  LPA does not sell, rent, or transfer your Personally Identifiable Information to any other third parties, except as otherwise provided in Section 2. Some of LPA's subsidiaries, affiliates, distributors, and entities involved in the operation of the Site may be located outside of your homecountry.  **By using LPA's Site, you consent to the transfer of your Personally Identifiable Information to these parties.**  

Auttomatic hosts the Blog on this Site through its website at WordPress.com.  LPA does not have access to the e-mail address(es) that you provide to Auttomatic to register for the Blog.  If you provide any information to Auttomatic, including any information you submit while using the Blog, you will be subject to Auttomatic's Privacy Policy on WordPress.com. 

**4.   _How Information Shared By LPA Is Used By Its Distributors_**

LPA's distributors may use your e-mail address to contact you about special offers, send you promotional material, or to track product warranties, repairs, and service inquiries. ** ** Once Personally Identifiable Information is shared with LPA distributors, you will be subject to that distributor's privacy policy or practices. 

While LPA will seek to require its affiliates, subsidiaries, and distributors to follow appropriate privacy policies and security measures, LPA does not bear responsibility for the actions or policies of any third party, and you should review the privacy practices of such third parties prior to providing any of your Personally Identifiable Information on the Site or the Blog.  If you would like more information about any third party receiving your Personally Identifiable Information, please contact LPA at the contact information provided in Section 9 of this Privacy Policy. 

**5.   _Security And Encryption_ **

**LPA does not currently use SSL encryption technology to secure Personally Identifiable Information that you provide to LPA on the Site.**   As a result, Personally Identifiable Information that you submit to the Site may not be secure.  LPA does use a secure server which  encrypts information transmitted between your browser and our server. Our security policies are reviewed periodically and revised as required.  The servers and databases for the Site that contain Personally Identifiable Information are stored in a physically secure and climate controlled off-site facility.  We protect against data loss by backing-up data, performing consistency checks, and restricting access to information on our servers and in our databases.  It is important to remember that whatever you transmit or disclose online can be collected and used by others or unlawfully intercepted by third parties. 

**6.   _Third Party Links_ **

Our Site may contain external links to third partywebsites.  We have no control over, and are not responsible for, the content of, or information gathered by these other websites.  Any Personally Identifiable Information collected by such third parties is subject to such third parties' privacy policies.  The third party owners of these Sites, except LPA distributors and Automattic, which hosts the Blog, do not have access to the Personally Identifiable Information collected on the LPA Site.  These third parties may themselves set and access their own cookies on your computer if you choose to have cookies enabled in your browser and you access their websites.  Third parties' use of cookies is subject to their own privacy policies. 

**7. _EU GDPR Compliance_**

This entire Privacy Policy is intended to comply with EU GDPR. If any portion of this Privacy Policy is not compliant with EU GDPR, then the EU GDPR has precedence over any such portion and that portion is considered null and void.

The LPA Data Privacy Officer can be contacted directly, using the contact information at the end of this policy, regarding any of the following:

  * Inquiries regarding this Privacy Policy or the EU GDPR compliance of LPA.
  * Requests for personal information held by LPA regarding a personally identifiable EU citizen by that citizen.
  * Requests for removal of any personally identifiable information by the EU citizen who owns the information.  

When contacting the LPA Data Privacy Officer, please state the nature of your inquiry/request and provide contact information so we can return the result of your inquiry/request. 

**_8.   Notification Of Changes_ **

LPA reserves the right, at any time and without notice, to add to, change, update or modify this Privacy Policy simply by posting such change, update, or modification on the Site. Any such change, update or modification will be effective immediately upon posting on the Site.  If at anypoint LPA decides to use Personally Identifiable Information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we may notify you by way of an e-mail or some other means. Your continued use of the Site shall constitute your acceptance of such revised Privacy Policy.  Since thisPrivacy Policy may change from time to time, you should review it periodically before you provide any additional Personally Identifiable Information anywhere on the Site. 

**9.    _LPA Privacy Policy Contact Information_**

Gary Brown (Data Privacy Officer)

Lab Partners Associates, Inc.

21 Gregory Drive, Suite 140

South Burlington, VT  05403

Telephone:  (802) 658-0038

Facsimile:  (802) 658-6125

Email:  [DPO@lpadesign.com](mailto:DPO@lpadesign.com?Subject=LPA%20Privacy%20Policy%20Inquiry)

_Last Revised 05/18_
